Finding Aid for Ralph A. Sawyer Papers 1918-1978
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Sound Recordings
  - Recordings of speeches made over German radio 1954, 2 reel-to-reel tapes (Box 12)
March 10, 1947; March 20, 1947; April 2, 1947
Goodridge, Edwin T.
April 28, 1948
Gillieson, A. H.
July 22, 1948
Goldberg, Leo
Sept. 28, 1959
Gomberg, Henry J.
Dec. 9, 1954
Gosling, L. A. Peter
Aug. 9, 1974
Goudsmit, Sam A.
May 6, 1947
Griffin, Clare Elmer, 1892-
Oct.9, 1947; Nov. 22, 1947
Guggenheim Foundation
Nov. 19, 1941; Nov. 30, 1937
Gunn, Rose
Feb. 22, 1956
Haber, William, 1899-
Sept. 25, 1951 (in the National Research Council, Commission on Human Resources file)
Hanau, Richard
March 17, 1952
Hansen, Gerhard
May 25, 1946; Nov. 30, 1959; Aug. 18, 1960; Nov. 15, 1960; Jan. 20, 1961; July 28, 1961
Dec. 15, 1947 (in Michigan. University. Physics Dept. correspondence)
Jan. 1, 1954; and Aug. 28, 1954 (in the Travel-Germany correspondence)
Harnwell, G. P.
Oct.13, 1950
Harrison, George R
Feb. 20, 1948; April 22, 1948; May 4, 1948; May 17, 1948; June 1, 1948; and Dec. 14, 1950
Aug. 5, 1940; Oct. 15, 1940; Oct. 28, 1941; Feb. 7, 1942; Jan. 31, 1957; and March 1, 1957 (in the Optical Society of America files); Jan. 29, 1942
Hawley, Amos H
May 15, 1964
Haynes, Phillip R.
Aug. 30, 1964
Hayward, Sidney C.
May 2, 1947
Heineman, D. N.
May 22, 1961
Heneman, H. J.
Jun 1, 1954; Aug. 11, 1954
Herrberg, Gerhard
Dec. 1971
Herzberg, G.
Dec. 1, 1961
Hess, R.E.
Oct.6, 1953
Heston, William
July 3, 1963
Hilberry, Clarence B.
Nov. 17, 1959; Feb. 5, 1954
Adam Hilger LTD (Optical Instrumt. Makers)
Jun 7, 1940
von Hippel, A.
Aug. 2, 1946
Hobbs, Lindsey M.
Feb. 1, 1960; Jan. 20, 1960
Hobbs, William H.
Oct.22, 1948
Howe, Harold
Oct.8, 1964; Oct.22, 1964; Nov. 7, 1964
Howlett, B.A.
Jun 3, 1949
Hoyt, Gordon
April 9, 1953; undated
Hughes, A.L.
Nov. 24, 1947
Hughes, T.P.
Dec. 12, 1961
Hulburt, Ed
Dec. 1, 1953; Feb. 3, 1947
Hussey, G. F., Jr.
Dec. 6, 1946; Dec. 21, 1946
Hutchisson, Elmer
Jan. 2, 1962; Jan. 5, 1962; Jan. 15, 1962; Jan. 19, 1962; Jan. 3, 1962; Nov. 16, 1961; Oct.11, 1946
Ihrig, Harry K.
Dec. 2, 1959
Irish, P. R. (Beth. Steel)
Nov. 3, 1952; Dec. 29, 1952
Jarrell, Richard F.
Oct.11, 1943; Oct.27, 1943
Jenkins, F.A.
April 11, 1941; Jun 1, 1941; Jun 10, 1941; Jun 20, 1941; March 12, 1941; Aug. 28, 1941; July 19, 1937
Johns Hopkins Univ.
Oct.25, 1948
Johnson, G. W.
Sept. 4, 1950; Sept. 20, 1950; April 19, 1948; Jun 27, 1948
Johnson, Jerry
Feb. 1, 1952
Jones, Donald W.
Jun 21, 1950
Jones, Herbert W.
Feb. 5, 1965
Jones, Keven R.
April 17, 1950
Jones & Laughlin Steel Corp.
May 19, 1969
Journal of the Optical Society of America
Feb. 10, 1973; Nov. 20, 1973; Nov. 27, 1968
Kahn, Reuben L.
Sept. 28, 1959
Keeley, Joseph
Aug. 21, 1964
Kelleher, Alfred
Jun 15, 1964; March 10
Kelly, Everett Lowell, 1905-
Jan. 27, 1959; Jan. 30, 1959; and July 8, 1960 (in the Michigan. University. Office of Research Administration files)
Keniston, Hayward, 1883-1970.
Jan. 13, 1947 and July 1957 (in the Graduate Schools, Ranking file)
July 2, 1946 (in the Joint Task Force 1 correspondence)
Kennard, D. C. Jr.
Jan. 17, 1968
Kleffel, O.
Oct.21, 1954
Klein, Elias
Feb. 1968
Klopsteg, Paul E.
Aug. 8, 1967
Knowles, Hugh Shaler, 1904-
June 14, 1954 (in the American Institute of Physics files)
Knudsen, Vern O.
Dec. 3, 1947
Koch, Harlan C.
Jun 19, 1964
Kock, Winston E.
July 17, 1964
Kraus, Edward H.
Jun 12, 1944
Kruger, P. G.
March 14, 1950; Dec. 6, 1949
Ladney, Michael, Jr.
Jan. 22, 1963
Lathem, Edward Connery
Sept. 9, 1964; July 28, 1955; Aug. 10, 1955; Aug. 25, 1955
Lake Superior State College
April 16, 1970
Lee, John J.
April 29, 1964
Leeds & Northrup Co.
Aug. 7, 1940
Line, Winfield
Feb. 12, 1954
Los Alamos Scientific Lab.
Jan. 13, 1947; Feb. 7, 1947 (LG Hawkins); Feb. 21, 1947; Jan. 8, 1947 (AE Deyre); Sept. 27, 1946; Nov. 6, 1946 (MA O'Brien); Nov. 27, 1946 (JE Harris); Dec. 4, 1946 (RC Smith); Dec. 6, 1946 (S Newburger, Jr.)
MacAdam, David L.
April 2, 1969; March 26, 1971
MacBeth Corporation
Jun 17, 1958
McMath, Robert R.
Oct.6, 1959
McMillin, J. B.
Dec. 6, 1951
McQuesten, Mrs. Herbert E.
Jan. 29, 1964; Oct.17, 1952; Dec. 4, 1952
Mack, Mrs. Julian E.
Feb. 5, 1968; Feb. 5, 1954
Majumdar, K.
April 15, 1970
Marley, Faye
July 1, 1960
Masterson, Keith D.
March 16, 1966; Feb. 28, 1966
Meader, George, 1907-
Aug. 25, 1960; April 11, 1961; March 28, 1962; and May 21, 1962 (in the Michigan University Office of Research Administration files); Oct.9, 1954
Meggers, William F.
Oct.4, 1944
Mendenhall, W. K., Jr.
March 8, 1958
Metropolis, Nicholas
Jan. 18, 1943
Meyer, Charles F.
May 29, 1944
Mich. College of Mining & Tech.
Jun 5, 1959; Jun 3, 1959; May 28, 1959; May 7, 1959
Mich. State College
April 4, 1952; April 18, 1952
Miller, Bruce J.
April 3, 1953; April 21, 1953
Miller, Freeman D.
May 30, 1977
Minn.-Honeywell Regulator Co.
Jun, 9, 1958
Henry Allen Moe
Feb. 1, 1966; Dec. 13, 1965; Jun 30, 1964; March 11, 1953; March 23, 1953
Moore, A. D.
Jan. 3, 1947
Mulder, Harlan J.
April 18, 1966
Mulliken, R. S.
Dec. 19, 1942
Murphy, Irene
May 15, 1960
Murphy, John E.
April 3, 1959
National Bureau of Standards
Jun 5, 1951; Jan. 30, 1950; Feb. 26, 1947
National Research Council
Feb. 12, 1958; Feb. 4, 1949
National Science Foundation
Nov. 13, 1963
Naval Surface Weapons Ctr.
Jan. 6, 1978; Dec. 10, 1970
Nelson, Donald F.
Nov. 8, 1965
Newburn, H. K.
Dec. 14, 1949
Niehuss, Marvin L.
Sept. 26, 1959; Aug. 30, 1956
Norman, A. G.
Jun 18, 1965
NW Univ. College of Liberal Arts, Dept. of Physics
May 8, 1930; Jun 2, 1930; Jun 7, 1930
O'Connor, T. J.
Sept. 28, 1961
Olson, William C.
Nov. 23, 1971
Optical Society of America
May 6, 1971
Oregon State University
July 15, 1970
Otero, Jose M
Sept. 14, 1961
Owens, James S.
Jun 8, 1971; Sept. 29, 1959
Paganelli, E.
Aug. 6, 1948
Page, Thornton
Jan. 25, 1948
Parker, J. W.
Sept. 26, 1947
Parsons, Carey Evlya
March 7, 1953
Parsons, W. S.
Dec. 11, 1946; Dec. 15, 1947
Paschen, F.
Sept. 15, 1926; Dec. 2, 1927; May 12, 1928; May 16, 1928; Oct. 7, 1929; June 20, 1936; July 20, 1936; Dec. 4, 1927; Sept. 16, 1926
Pasvolsky, Leo
May 19, 1947
Peckham, Donald C.
May 9, 1964
Peet, Bert W.
Dec. 4, 1946
Peet, Max M
July 21, 1948
Pendill, Claudius G.
July 6, 1950
Penney, William George, 1909-
Aug. 22, 1946 (in the Joint Task Force 1 correspondence file)
Pergamon Institute
Dec. 10, 1956
Perkins, John A.
Jan. 7, 1958
Phelps, Fred
Sept. 29, 1977
Phinney, Elizabeth
Jun 10, 1959
Platt, John
April 13, 1955; Jan. 9, 1955; May 3, 1946
Prentice Hall Inc.
Feb. 18, 1953; July 11, 1952; Aug. 28, 1951; Jan. 12, 1951; Jan. 10, 1951; March 21, 1951; April 10, 1951; April 24, 1951; Jun 20, 1950; Feb. 24, 1950; July 21, 1950; Nov. 8, 1950; July 13, 1950; July 21, 1950; July 31, 1950; Aug. 9, 1950; Dec. 16, 1949; Feb. 9, 1950; March 13, 1950; May 9, 1950; May 19, 1950
Nov. 22, 1949; Aug. 4, 1948; Sept. 20, 1948; May 17, 1948; May 21, 1948; April 2, 1948; March 13, 1948; April 6, 1948; April 14, 1948; May 27, 1948; July 9, 1948; July 30, 1948; Jun 23, 1947; April 17, 1946; April 2, 1946
March 3, 1945; Oct.15, 1945; Dec. 15, 1944; Nov. 9, 1944; July 27, 1943; Aug. 31, 1944; Jan. 31, 1944; Oct.5, 1944; Sept. 14, 1944; Sept. 28, 1944; Jun 15, 1944; Jun 19, 1944; Oct.20, 1944; March 3, 1944; Feb. 5, 1944; Feb. 11, 1944; Jan. 19, 1944; Feb. 3, 1944; May 7, 1943; Dec. 7, 1943; July 21, 1943; March 15, 1943
Jan. 21, 1942; Jan. 26, 1942; Feb. 13, 1942; March 31, 1942; Dec. 30, 1942; May 15, 1937; March 6, 1941; Jan. 15, 1941; July 16, 1940; May 8, 1939; July 26, 1938; Oct.28, 1938; April 15, 1977; March 11, 1937; Feb. 26, 1937
Price, Derek John deSolla, 1922-
Oct. 20, 1965
Putzold, E.Y.
March 14, 1955; March 23, 1955
Prine, Arthur C.
Sept. 30, 1959
Pryor, Millard H.
Jun 18, 1953
Radford School, El Paso
Sept. 24, 1949; May 25, 1949
Radock, Michael
Feb. 6, 1963
Randall, Harrison McAllister, 1870-1969.
July 7, 1919; July 25, 1919; Aug. 21, 1919; May 24, 1921; and June 30, 1927 (in the Michigan. University Physics Dept. correspondence file)
Nov. 4, 1963 (in the Michigan. University. Rackham Retirement file)
Rassweiler, Gerald M.
Nov. 15, 1972
Ratner, Sidney
Feb. 20, 1957
Reader, Joseph
Feb. 24, 1970
Regents of the Univ. of Michigan
Aug. 9, 1954
Reitner, H. L.
March 1, 1958
Republicans and Independents for Johnson
Aug. 13, 1964
Richardson, Harold W.
May 26, 1964
Riddle, F.L.
July 18, 1950
Rieser, Leonard
April 3, 1961
Rollwagen, Walter
Nov. 8, 1947
Romney, George
March 23, 1964
Rosenhaupt, Hans
Jun 15, 1964; Aug. 24, 1964
Ross, Gil
Oct.2, 1959
Rudnick, Isadore, Robert Satten, L.P. Delsasso
May 1964
Rugg, Harold G.
Oct.30, 1948
Ruthven, Alexander Grant, 1882-1971.
July 10, 1946 (in the Michigan. University. Rackham Appointment file)
Sasscer, Harrison
July 21, 1964
Sawyer, George A.
Dec. 20, 1954
Schmidt, Frank K.
Jun 10, 1964
Schoeffel, M. F.
Oct.21, 1954
Scribner, Bourdon F.
March 10, 1961
Seitz, Frederick, 1911-
Feb. 24, 1961; March 14, 1961; Jan. 3, 1962; Jan. 15, 1962; Oct. 8, 1962; June 22, 1967; July 11, 1967; Oct. 10, 1967; Oct. 12, 1967; Jan. 6, 1970; June 6, 1970.
Oct. 2, 1956; Nov. 7, 1956; Dec. 7, 1956; May 17, 1961; Dec. 13, 1961; March 19, 1962 and Jan. 10, 1964 (in the American Institute of Physics correspondence file)
Nov. 10, 1964; Oct. 20, 1965; Nov. 15, 1965; July 19, 1968; and Nov. 15, 1968 (in the National Academy of Sciences, National Bureau of Standards correspondence file)
Shankland, R.S.
Dec. 7, 1966
Shapiro, Rubin
Jun 3, 1952; July 7, 1952
Shilling, C. W.
Nov. 18, 1957
Siegel, Keeve M.
Jan. 4, 1973
Sleyak, Edward J.
May 12, 1964; Sept. 29, 1959
Smith, Walter Bedell
March 7, 1955
Smith, Ralph Carlisle
May 15, 1950
Smyth, Henry D.
Sept. 28, 1954
Snow, Charles Percy, 1905-
July 8, 1960 and July 25, 1960 (in the American Institute of Physics correspondence file)
Solberg, T. A.
May 17, 1950
Spight, Lon D.
March 2, 1976
Spurr, Stephen H.
March 11, 1969
Steding, H. Richard
May 9, 1960
Steere, William C.
March 31, 1949
Stevenson, William E.
July 27, 1949; May 28, 1948
Stewart, G. W.
Jan. 6, 1948
Stirton, W. E.
April 22, 1959; Sept. 25, 1959
Stratton,Thomas F
Sept. 15, 1965
Struve, Otto, 1898-1963.
Aug. 19, 1960 (in the Michigan. University. Office of Research Administration correspondence)
Swets & Zeitlinger
Feb. 18, 1960; March 14, 1959; May 14, 1959; Jun 17, 1959
Takamine, T.
March 22, 1950; Dec. 23, 1949
Taylor, J. H.
March 5, 1965; Oct.14, 1965
Taylor, William Randolph, 1895
Oct. 15, 1946; Aug. 5, 1948; and Aug. 17, 1948; Jan. 30, 1947
Thailand Embassy
May 7, 1955
Thompson, Charles C.
Feb. 27, 1959
Thatcher, Everett W.
Feb. 24, 1947; March 17, 1947; Jun 20, 1947
Thompson, L.T.E., Dr.
Feb. 15, 1964
van Tongeren, W.
Feb. 20, 1948
Townsend and Bottum, Inc.
Jan. 23, 1944
Uehlinger, A.E.
undated
Ultra Carbon Corp.
Jun 10, 1963
Umphrey, James R.
Jun 3, 1964
United Airlines
July 15, 1963; Aug. 30, 1963
Univ. of California Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory
April 25, 1969
University of Detroit
April 2, 1951
Upthegrove, Nelson
May 17, 1948
Urey, Harold C.
March 17, 1948
U.S. Naval Weapons Laboratory
March 28, 1966
Van Pelt, J. R.
Oct.28, 1959
Van Vleck, John Hasbrouck, 1899-
April 16, 1969
Varney, Robert Nathan, 1910-
Feb. 11, 1948; March 25, 1948; April 14, 1948; April 15, 1948; and Sept. 14, 1949.
Aug. 29, 1941; Sept. 11, 1941; Oct. 24, 1941; Nov. 24, 1941; Jan. 15, 1942; Feb. 9, 1942 (in the Naval Proving Ground correspondence); Sept. 4, 1949
Vely, C.J.
Aug. 14, 1964
Vivian, Weston Edward, 1924
May 5, 1965 (in the Michigan. University. Office of Research Administration. Indirect costs file)
Van Vleck, J. H.
April 16, 1969
Walker, L. Cisler
Sept. 26, 1959
Walter, Erich A.
Sept. 29, 1959
Warga, Mary E.
Dec. 13, 1968; March 14, 1944
Weaver, Bennett
April 30, 1964
Weber, Louis R.
Dec. 9, 1969
Wedemeyer, George
Sept. 29, 1959
White, Albert Easten, 1884-1956.
July 1, 1941; Aug. 20, 1941; and Jan. 23, 1942 (in the Naval Proving Ground correspondence file)
White, Elsie S.
April 11, 1959
White, Leonard D.
Nov. 10, 1957; April 26, 1948
White, Marsh W.
Aug. 7, 1967
Whitney, W. R.
Oct.25, 1948; Oct.30, 1948
Whittemore, Richard
Aug. 2, 1948
Wille, Don M.
May 19, 1964
Williams, Dudley
Nov. 30, 1960
Wilson, Art L.
Jan. 22, 1958; March 7, 1958
Wilson, Chas. W.
Feb. 26, 1970
Wilson, Leslie J.
Dec. 5, 1963
Wittman, N. O.
Oct.10, 1961
Wolfle, Dael
Sept. 29, 1954
Wood, William R.
Aug. 14, 1963
Youngblood, Curtis T.
May 9, 1947
Youty, P. N.
Oct.21, 1963
Zink, Theodore H.
July 15, 1958
Related Material
Other materials in the library of related interest include files of the Horace H. Rackham School of Graduate Studies from the period when Sawyer was dean, and records of the Michigan Memorial Phoenix Project during Sawyer's directorship.